# Michael Gebhart

## **Gameplay Programmer**

Team player with a focus on C++ and Unreal Engine. Professional game development experience with UE 3, 4 and 5.

Motivated to learn new skills and build on my C++ skills with the goal of leading technical teams myself.

Inspired to make games reaching players worldwide!

**Portfolio**: www.michael-gebhart.com • **GitHub**: www.github.com/m-gebhart **Mail**: mail@michael-gebhart.com • **LinkedIn**: www.linkedin.com/in/m-gebhart

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## 09/2023 - present

# **Abstraction Games B.V.** - Valkenswaard, NL (Remote)

Jr. Programmer resuming work on *Gigantic: Rampage Edition* (Gearbox Publishing, 2024)

- Used C++, UC, Kismet and Flash, AS, Scaleform to further improve UI, e.g.:
  - Redesign of UI screens (e.g., character selection, loadouts) in collaboration with design team to meet specific publisher requests.
  - o Finalized voice UI system in collaboration with engine team.
  - Used Kismet scripting for UI guidance in tutorials.
  - Gamepad navigation fixes.
  - Localization fixes.
- Utilized JSON to bugfix data-driven hero and skill system.
- Post-Launch Support, e.g.:
  - New upgrade abilities for heroes from initial roster.
  - Extended clone AI behaviour (*Kajir*'s specialty, most recently introduced hero).
  - o Applied new metric system for better match performance rating behaviour.
  - o Rapid removal of hero bugs and exploits based on player feedback.

#### 03/ - 07/2023

## **Abstraction Games B.V.** - Valkenswaard, NL (Remote)

C++ Programming Intern for Gigantic: Rampage Edition (Gearbox Publishing, 2024)

- Joined the core programming team to revitalize a UE3 game.
- UI programming with C++, UC and Flash, AS, Scaleform:
  - o Redesign of menu and HUD elements (e.g., voice, in-game and shield system).
  - Better console UI navigation by creating new functionalities for footer action bar (e.g., custom controls, animation options for button prompts).
  - o New HUD indications for skill status timers.

## 11/2020 - 12/2022

#### Macromedia University of Applied Sciences - Cologne, GER

Student Assistant for Game Design & Development program management

# 11/2020 - 03/2021

# Adventure Works LLC - Miami, US (Remote)

Game Programming Intern for Far Away (later revealed as Ari Baktu and the Anytime Elevator)

- Used C++ and UE4 / 5 to assist development of a side-scrolling narrative action game.
- Supported the core gameplay team with rapid prototyping, bugfixing, gameplay features and in-engine level design tools.

#### **EDUCATION**

09/2018 - 08/2023

Cologne Game Lab at Cologne University of Applied Sciences (TH Köln)

BA Digital Games - Game Programming

## **SHIPPED COMMERCIAL TITLES**

Gigantic: Rampage Edition

Release: April 9<sup>th</sup>, 2024 Genre: MOBA / 3<sup>rd</sup> Person Action Online Game o Developer: Abstraction Games B.V. (Original release by Motiga)

o I joined the project in March 2023 to support its last one-and-a-half years of development. Following its release in April 2024, I stayed on the project until July 2024 to incorporate as much player feedback as possible (before then being allocated to another internal project (tba)).

## **ACADEMIC TEAM PROJECT EXPERIENCE**

The Big Banger (2021)	Gameplay Programmer • Team of Six • Unity, C#, AR Foundation
Mobile AR Educational Game	<ul> <li>Implemented player feedback systems (e.g., movement, audio, UI).</li> </ul>
	• Designed control systems (i.e., translating 2D touch input to a 3D space).
Mayhaemsters (2020)	Project Lead, Gameplay Programmer • Team of Five • Unreal Engine 4, C++
Local Multiplayer Action Game	Pitched initial concept.
	<ul> <li>Team management by overseeing tasks and deadlines.</li> </ul>
	<ul> <li>Co-Implemented game systems (e.g., input, vehicle movement,</li> </ul>
	animation, audio, UI).
Underground Berlin (2020)	JavaScript Programmer, Web Designer • Team of Four • HTML / CSS, JavaScript
Alternate Reality Game	• Scripted static and dynamic websites as part of connected puzzle games.
A Dystopian Murder Show (2019)	Gameplay Programmer • Team of Five • Unity, C#
Action Platformer	<ul> <li>Created majority of game systems (e.g., controls, combat, UI,</li> </ul>
	animations).
	Polished game for release on itch.io.
SKILLS	
Technical Experiences:	• C++, C#

SITIELS	
Technical Experiences:	• C++, C#
	<ul> <li>JavaScript, HTML / CSS, ActionScript, Scaleform, UnrealScript</li> </ul>
	• Unreal Engine 3 - 5, OpenGL, Unity, FMOD, Rider, Adobe Animate
	Git, Perforce
	<ul> <li>Vegas Movie Studio, MS Office Suit, Jira</li> </ul>
Languages:	German (native), English